Guide to the Rosetta Reitz Papers, 1929-2008
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Reference Materials Series 1946-2005, (23 boxes)
  - Books
    - Pearson, Barry Lee. Sounds good to me: the bluesman's story. Philadelphia: University of Pennsylvania Press, 1984. (Box 55)
    - Placksin, Sally. American women in jazz, 1900 to the present: their words, lives, and music. [S. l.]: Wideview, 1982. (Box 55)
      (notes in margins) (extensive binding damage; loose pages)
    - Pleasants, Henry. The great American popular singers. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1974. (Box 55)
      (notes in margins) (notes in front endpaper) (page of plates defaced)
    - Poling, James. Esquire's world of jazz. New York: Esquire, 1962. (Box 55)
    - Rampersad, Arnold. The life of Langston Hughes, Volume II: 1941-1967: I dream a world. New York: Oxford, 1988. (Box 55)
    - Ramsey, Frederic; Smith, Charles Edward. (eds.) Jazzmen. London; New York: Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1967. (Box 55)
    - Reisner, Robert George. (comp.) The literature of jazz: a preliminary bibliography. New York: The New York Public Library, 1954. (Box 55)
    - Reitz, Rosetta. Menopause: a positive approach. Radnor, Penn.: Chilton Book Co., 1977. (Box 55)
    - Reitz, Rosetta. Menopause: a positive approach. New York: Penguin, 1979. (Box 55)
    - Reitz, Rosetta. Ouder worden voor beginners: vrouwen over de overgang, liefde en seksualiteit. (Menopause: a positive approach). Amsterdam: Feministische Uitgeverij Sara, 1985. (Box 55)
    - Reitz, Rosetta. Wechseljahre: ermutigung zu einem neuen verstandnis. (Menopause: a positive approach). Hamburg: Rowohlt, 1990. (Box 55)
    - Reitz, Rosetta. Mushroom Cookery. New York: Grammercy Publishing, 1965. (Box 55)
    - Reitz, Rosetta; Geisler, Joan. Where to go in Greenwich Village. Published by the authors, 1971. (Box 55)
    - Rich, Alan. The Simon and Schuster listener's guide to jazz. New York: Simon and Schuster, 1980. (Box 56)
    - Roberts, John Storm. Black music for two worlds. New York: William Morrow and Company, 1974. (Box 56)
    - Rose, Al. Eubie Blake. New York: Schirmer, 1979. (Box 56)
    - Rudwick, Bracey Meier. Black matriarchy: myth or reality? Belmont: Wadsworth, 1971. (Box 56)
    - Russell, Ross. Jazz style in Kansas City and the Southwest. Berkeley, Calif.: University of California, 1971. (Box 56)
    - Sackheim, Eric. (comp.) The blues line: a collection of blues lyrics. New York: Schirmer Books, 1969. (Box 56)
    - Sampson, Henry T. Blacks in blackface: a source book on early black musical shows. Metuchen, N.J.: Scarecrow, 1980. (Box 56)
    - Sanchez, Sister Sonia. A blues book for blue black magical women. Detroit: Broadside Press, 1974. (Box 56)
    - Santelli, Robert. The big book of blues: a biographical encyclopedia. London: Penguin, 1993. (Box 56)
    - Schiedt, Duncan. The jazz state of Indiana. Pittsboro, Ind.: Duncan P. Schiedt, 1977. (Box 56)
    - Schiffman, Jack. Uptown: the story of Harlem’s Apollo Theatre. New York: Cowles, 1971. (Box 56)
      (four pages of plates defaced)
    - Schiffman, Jack. Harlem Heyday: a pictorial history of modern black show business and Apollo Theatre. Buffalo, N.Y.: Prometheus Books, 1984. (Box 56)
    - Schuller, Gunther. The swing era: the development of jazz 1930-1945. New York; Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1989. (Box 56)
    - Shapiro, Nat; Hentof, Natt. (eds.) Hear me talkin' to ya: the story of jazz as told by the men who made it. New York: Dover, 1955. (Box 56)
    - Shaw, Arnold. Honkers and shouters: the golden years of rhythm and blues. New York: Collier, 1978. (Box 56)
    - Shefter, Bert. (comp. and ed.) Hazel Scott easy-to-play boogie-woogie. (instructional song book) New York: Robbins Music, 1944. (Box 56)
    - Short, Bobby. Black and white baby. New York: Curtis, 1971. (Box 56)
    - Sidran, Ben. Black talk. New York: Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1971. (Box 56)
    - Simon, George T. The big bands. New York: Collier, 1967. (Box 56)
    - Smith, Bessie; Albertson, Chris (comp.). Bessie Smith: empress of the blues. New York: Schirmer, 1975. (Box 57)
      (notes in margins) (pp. 15, 16 defaced) (binding damage)
    - Smith, Willie the Lion; Hoefer, George. Music on my mind: the memoirs of an American pianist. New York: Da Capo, 1964. (Box 57)
    - Stearns, Marshall W. The story of jazz. London; Oxford; New York: Oxford University Press, 1956. (Box 57)
    - Stewart, Charles; Harrison, Paul Carter. Chuck Stewart’s jazz files. Boston: Little Brown, 1985. (Box 57)
    - Stewart-Baxter, Derrick. Ma Rainey and the classic blues singers. New York: Stein and Day, 1970. (Box 57)
    - Stoddard, Tom. Pops Foster: the autobiography of a New Orleans jazzman. Berkely; Los Angeles; London: University of California Press, 1971. (Box 57)
    - The story of the saxophone: its history and its uses. Elkhart, Ind: Buescher Band Instrument Co, 1923. (Box 57)
      (extensive binding damage)
    - Taylor, Billy. Jazz piano: a jazz history. Dubuque, Iow.: Wm. C. Brown Company, 1982, 1983. (Box 57)
    - Toll, Robert C. Blacking up: the minstrel show in Nineteenth-Century America. London; New York: Oxford, 1974. (Box 57)
    - Traill, Sinclair; Lascelles, Gerald. Just jazz: three. London: Landsborough Publications, 1959. (Box 57)
    - Trolle, Frank H. James P. Johnson: father of the stride piano, part two. (discography) Alphen aan de Rijn, the Netherlands: Micrography, 1981. (Box 57)
      (handwritten list of artists front endpaper)
    - Tuska, Jon. The films of Mae West. Secaucus, N.J.: The Citadel Press, 1973. (Box 57)
    - Unterbink, Mary. Jazz Women at the Keyboard. Jefferson, N.C.; London: Mcfarland, 1983. (Box 57)
      (with note and signature by author) (notes in margins)
    - Wald, Elijah. Global Minstrels: voices of world music. New York; London: Routledge, 2007. (Box 57)
    - Wald, Elijah. Escaping the delta: Robert Johnson and the invention of the blues. New York: Amistad, 2004. (Box 57)
    - Waters, Ethel. To me it’s wonderful. New York: Harper and Row, 1972. (Box 57)
      (notes in margins) (two pages of plates defaced)
    - Waters, Ethel.; Samuels, Charles. His eye is on the sparrow. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday and Company, 1951. (Box 57)
      (notes in margins, front endpaper) (binding damage) (back endpaper defaced)
    - Weissman, Dick. Blues: the basics. New York; London: Routledge, 2005. (Box 57)
    - Wenner, Hilda E.; Freilicher, Elizabeth. Here's to the women: 100 songs for and about American women. Syracuse University Press, 1987. (Box 57)
    - White, John. Billie Holiday: her life and times. New York: Universe, 1987. (Box 57)
      (notes in margins) (water damage)
    - Wilder, Alec; Maher, James T. (ed.). American popular song: the great innovators, 1900-1950. London; New York: Oxford, 1972. (Box 57)
    - Williams, Martin. Kings of Jazz: King Oliver. New York: A.S. Barnes, 1960. (Box 57)
    - Williams, Martin. Where's the melody?: a listener's introduction to jazz. Minerva Press, 1963. (Box 57)
    - Williams, Martin. Jazz heritage. New York; Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1985. (Box 57)
    - Williams, Martin. (ed.) Jazz panorama: from the pages of Jazz Review. New York: Collier Books, 1964. (Box 57)
    - Williams, Martin; Tucker, Mark (comp.). Singers and soloists of the swing bands. Washington, D.C.: Smithsonian Collection of Recordings, 1987. (Box 57)
    - Wilmer, Valerie. Jazz people. Indianapolis: Bobbs-Merrill, 1970. (Box 57)
    - Wilson, John W. The collector's jazz: modern. Philidelphia; New York: JB Lippincott Co., 1959. (Box 57)